France Kafka was a great Czech writer
who has come to own a part of the human
emotional Spectrum which we can now call
the Kafkaesque and which thanks to him
we're able better to recognize and to
gain a measure of perspective over and
relief from kafka's World Isn't Pleasant
it feels in many ways like a nightmare
and yet it's a place where many of us
will even if only for a time in the dark
periods of Our Lives end up we're in the
world defined by Kafka when we feel
powerless in front of authority judges
Aristocrats industrialists politicians
and most of all fathers when we feel
that our destiny is out of our control
when we're bullied humiliated and mocked
by society and especially by our own
families we're in kafka's orbit when
we're ashamed of our bodies of our
sexual urges and feel that the best
thing for us might be to be killed or
squashed without Mercy as if we were An
Inconvenient and rather disgusting bed
bug France Kafka was born in Prague in
1883 the eldest child of a terrifyingly
psychologically abusive father and a
mother who was too weak and in awe of
her husband to protect her boy as she
should have done Kafka grew up timid
bookish meek and full of self- hatred he
wanted to become a writer but it was out
of the question in his father's eyes so
one of the greatest German literary
Geniuses since gerter was forced to
spend his brief life on Earth working in
a series of jobs utterly beneath him in
a LW office and then an insurance
company he had a number of unsuccessful
relationships with women he couldn't
marry or raise a family and was
tormented by the strength of his sex
drive which made him constantly turn to
brothel and pornography Kafka published
very little in his lifetime just three
collections of short stories including
his best known work the metamorphosis
and he was entirely obscure and
unnoticed his gigantic postumus
reputation is based on three novels the
trial the castle and America which were
all unfinished because Kafka was so
dissatisfied with them he gave orders
that they be destroyed after his death
fortunately for Humanity these were
disobeyed it shouldn't sound puant or
reductive to suggest that one of the
major keys to understanding Kafka is to
Fathom the nature of his relationship
with his father Kafka never wrote
directly about this man in any of his
works but the psychology of the novels
is directly related to the Dynamics he
endured as the very unfortunate son of
Herman Kafka any boy who has ever felt
inadequate in front of or unloved by a
powerful father will at once relate to
what Kafka went through in his childhood
in November 1919 at the age of 36 5
years before his death kafa wrote a
47-page letter to Herman in which he
tried to explain how his childhood had
deformed him like many victims of abuse
Kafka never stopped hoping for some kind
of forgiveness from the person who had
so wronged him dearest father went the
letter you asked me recently why I
maintain that I'm so afraid of you as
usual I was unable to think of any
answer to your question partly for the
very reason that I am afraid of you and
partly because an explanation of the
grounds for this fear would mean going
into far more details than I could ever
keep in mind while talking the grown
Kafka abased himself before this father
what I would have needed was a little
encouragement a little friendliness but
I wasn't fit for that what was always
incomprehensible to me was your total
lack of feeling for the suffering and
shame you could inflict on me with your
words and judgments it was as though you
had no notion of your power kafa
complained of one particularly traumatic
incident when as a young boy he called
out for a glass of water and his
irritable father pulled the boy out of
his bed carried him out onto the balcony
and left him there to freeze in nothing
but his night shirt Kafka writes I was
quite obedient after that period but it
did me so much incalculable inner harm
even years afterwards I suffered from
the tormenting fancy that the huge man
my father the ultimate Authority would
come almost for no reason at all and
take me out of bed in the night and
carry me out onto the balcony and that
meant I was a mere nothing for him boys
need their father's permission to become
men and Herman Kafka didn't give France
a chance at a very early stage you
forbade me to speak your threat not a
word of contradiction and the raised
hand that accompanied it have been with
me ever since France's sense of
inadequacy was total I was weighed down
by your mere physical presence I
remember for instance how often we
undressed in the same bathing Hut there
was our skinny weakly slight you strong
tall broad I felt a miserable specimen
when we stepped out you holding me by my
hand a little skeleton unsteady
frightened of the water incapable of
copying your swimming strokes I was
frantic with
desperation it could hardly have been
worse except it was Kafka finished the
letter gave it to his mother Julie to
pass to Herman but typical of her
weakness and cowardice she didn't she
held on to it for a few days then
returned it to France and advised that
it would be better if her busy
hardworking husband never had to read
such a thing the poor son lacked the
courage ever to try again in the
Judgment kafka's great short story
written in 1912 a young businessman gor
is engaged to be married and lives in a
flat with his widowed father he's about
to get away from home the father is old
and frail gor tucks him up in bed but
then the father mysteriously regains his
strength brings upright Towers over goog
and denounces him for betraying everyone
his friends his father and the memory of
his mother goog can make only feeble
protests eventually the father condemns
goog to death by drowning and goog
obediently rushes out and plunges into
the nearby River after passing sentence
the father cries out you an innocent
child really but at heart you were a
diabolical human being the idea of
horrific AR arbitary judgment was to be
a constant in kafka's fiction it
reappears in the unfinished novel The
Trial written 2 years later but now
Kafka had developed it away from her
father to a vast legal apparatus with
judges lawyers guards and extensive
bureaucratic procedures when Joseph Kay
is arrested on the morning of his 30th
birthday he isn't told what he is
charged with he barely makes any attempt
to find out he feels so guilty inside he
just knows that he deserves punishment
he does try to declare in court that
he's innocent still without knowing what
the charge is and hires a lawyer but the
court gradually grinds him down he
becomes unable to think of anything
words fail him he can no longer do his
job properly and is defeated in the game
of office politics finally a year after
his arrest two grotesque looking
officials come to Joseph K's flat they
lead him to a quarry outside the city
and execute him by plunging a knife into
his heart between the judgment and the
trial Kafka wrote The Metamorphosis a
short story in which a traveling
salesman Gregor samama wakes up one
morning transformed into an insect akin
to a beetle or a bed bug it's a story of
self-disgust about the treachery of
family and like the trial about
terrifying arbitrary power when Gregor
crawls across the floor he is in danger
of being stamped on by his own father
Gregor's family find they manage quite
well without him they confine him to his
room and Chuck rubbish at him the family
hold a counsel and decide that the
insect in the bedroom can't really be
Gregor they start to refer to the insect
as it instead of him they decide that
somehow the insect has to go Gregor
listening agrees and dies quietly after
Gregor's death the family are slightly
ashamed of their behavior but only
slightly cfus suffered from ill health
for a lot of his life in 1924 when he
was 41 he developed lenial tuberculosis
which prevented him from eating almost
anything without huge pain he wrote a
short story his last called The Hunger
Artist it tells the story of a public
performer who makes his living
undertaking fasts for the pleasure of
the public one time he manages to fast
for 40 days but gradually the hunger
artist's audience gets bored of his work
however hard he fasts they're no longer
impressed he gets put in a dirty old
cage and weakens terribly before he dies
he asks for forgiveness and confesses
that he should never have been admired
since the reason he fasted was simply
that he couldn't find any food he
enjoyed shortly after he dies he's
replaced in his cage by a panther an
animal full of vigor whom the crowd love
and who has a voracious appetite a few
days after finishing the hunger Artis
Kafka died and was buried in the Jewish
cemetery in Prague within a few years of
his death his reputation began by the
second world war he was recognized as
one of the Great writers of the age not
withstanding all his close family were
gassed by the Germans in the Holocaust
he is a monument in German literary
history and at the same time he is a sad
ashamed terrified part of us all Kafka
once wrote that the task of literature
is to reconnect us with feelings that
might otherwise be unbearable to study
but which desperately need our attention
a book must he wrote be the axe for the
Frozen sea within us his books were
among the most touching frightening and
accurate axes ever written